# DAVID CRAWFORD

## Technical Writer | Editor

Houston, TX

281.660.2249

david.crawford1995@gmail.com

https://dg-crawford.github.io/writingportfolio/

#### **SUMMARY**

Specializes in technical topics with a proven ability to translate complex concepts into accessible language for non-technical audiences. Dedicated worker that meets deadlines 100% of the time and has received 97% positive customer feedback on content quality.

### **SKILLS**

- Copywriting & Content Writing
- Copy Editing & Proofreading
- Content Creation
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- Marketing Communications
- Technical Writing
- Microsoft Word, Excel & Outlook
- SharePoint
- Visio
- Confluence
- HTML

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Earned scholarship in writing from The Paisano literary magazine.
- Authored article published in Forbes magazine.
- Created a new Excel and Confluence process to automate essential information changes.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Technical Writer | VillageMD | Houston, TX

Sep 2021-Current

- Develop and maintain documentation, including job aids, medical protocols, and processes.
- Review and edit existing documentation in knowledge management database to maintain accuracy and relevancy.
- Interview subject matter experts (SMEs) to become familiar with processes to document.
- Wrote and launched a new knowledgebase in SharePoint that received an 85% satisfaction rating from users.
- Increased agent and provider engagement with knowledge database by 258%.
- Increased viewership of knowledge database and job aids by 290% since implementation of new website.
- Lead a team of executives and national directors to plan and execute medical protocol changes on both the call center and clinic levels.

#### Writer & Editor | Freelance | Houston, TX

Jun 2020-Sep 2021

- Delivered writing, editing, and proofreading services to individual and business clients. Ensured exceptional experiences through clear communication, consistent follow-up, and quality service delivery.
- Researched, wrote, and proofread 23 pages of keyword-rich website content, which immediately boosted the client's company rankings to the second page on Google searches and doubled organic leads from website traffic.
- Edited and rewrote a website and marketing materials for a business, resulting in a 75% increase in web traffic and a 200% increase in leads.

#### 

- Adhered to diverse tone and style specifications in alignment with project requirements to ensure web pages, blogs, and other marketing writing materials maintained the company's message.
- Built a reputation for creating accurate, grammatically sound content targeting specific audiences.

# Assistant Managing Editor | The Paisano | San Antonio, TX Aug 2018-Jan 2019

- Established a clear voice for the publication by developing and documenting a comprehensive style guide.
- Managed a group of 15 writers and editors who reduced publication errors through meticulous editing to elevate journal quality and accuracy.
- Contributed to 50% growth in social media engagement by selecting relevant, compelling journal content.
- Edited up to 12 news features, editorial articles, and opinion pieces weekly to ensure factual, concise, explicit, and grammatically accurate content.

#### Intern | Sagebrush Review | San Antonio, TX

Sep 2016-Jan 2017

- Expanded submissions by writing and launching a compelling email marketing campaign that targeted over 100 new leads at universities nationwide.
- Contributed to marketing operations by identifying, researching, and reporting on advertising opportunities.

# **EDUCATION**

# **BA in English Literature, Creative Writing concentration**

Univ. of Texas at San Antonio | San Antonio, TX